In this clip we are going to be talking about how to pick a topic for an interview.
If you're at a live sporting event and you are watching the game it's great to be there but you are working so you have to bring a note pad and take notes.
For instance if you're watching a professional football game you just don't want to say the score is 15 to 16, which is a weird score for a football game, I know, but you want to say "Wow, Tom Brady thrown 3 interceptions so far and the Patriots are still playing well."
You want to be able to critique the game as you watch it so when you pick a topic you go into the locker room or where ever the interview session is you will pick your topic and follow that topic, that's what you will be interviewing on.
So will kind of have your things planned out, that way you don't get into the locker room or the interview area and you're bumbling around and you don't know what you are talking about.
A lot of times reporters who are unprepared allow all the other reporters at the interview session to ask questions and then they'll just hold the mic.
There.
You can always tell who's prepared by who asks the most questions and who asks the fastest questions.
Because like I said, if you listen to the interviewee you know what he's talking about but if you come prepared to say well in the 3rd quarter you threw an interception what were you trying to do.
That's what I mean by critique you have to have a topic ready to interview the subject about so that everything can move quickly.